

Contact Details

philipjonlewis@gmail.com +63 916 443 2043

Tech Stack

Front-End

- HTML5
- CSS + SCSS
- Tailwind
- Typescript + Javascript
- ReactJS
- NextJS
- GatsbyJS
- Svelte

Back-End

- NodeJS
- ExpressJS
- REST/RESTful API's

Database

- NoSQL MongoDB
- Redis
- GraphQL
- SQL PostgreSQL

Bundlers & Compilers

- Webpack
- ViteParcel
- 1 41001

Other Tech

- Docker
- Firebase
- Supabase
- Redux
- Redux Toolkit
- RTK Query

CMS

Strapi

UX & UI

- Figma
- AdobeXD

Architecture & 3D

- AutoCAD
- Sketchup
- Vray
- Lumion

Adobe Suite

- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- InDesign

GitHub Account

github.com/philipjonlewis

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/philipjonlewis

Philip Jon Echavez Lewis UAP, PIA

Duly Registered & Licensed Architect, Republic of the Philippines Professional Regulatory Commission License Number: 00383344

Professional Summary

A highly skilled and driven self-taught full-stack developer, I possess over six years of experience in the Architecture, Engineering and Construction (AEC) industry. My background as a licensed architect has honed my ability to analyze and solve complex problems, while my proficiency in software engineering has enabled me to build front-end and back-end software with technical competence.

In previous roles, I have effectively managed the design and production of multiple projects, and have excelled in client presentations and coordination with engineers and suppliers. I am committed to producing high-quality work and am eager to further my growth as a multi-disciplinary developer and team-player for your organization.

Work Experience

Owner & Full Stack Software Engineer

WestXDX - Sole Proprietor

2021-2022

- Owner & Full Stack Developer of WestXDX, a one man startup currently working on bespoke software for the AEC (Architecture, Engineering & Construction) Industry. Current projects include the ff:
 - TapTapTask (taptaptask.com) a task-management tool for phase-based projects. front end code made with Vite, ReactJS, Redux Toolkit, RTK Query, CSS + SASS and backend code made with NodeJS+Express & MongoDB. All written in typescript. (full code on my github profile)
 - QuickNotes (quicknotesbyphilip.netlify.app) a minimalist block style editor made with typescript, google firebase for the database, React, Vite, EditorJS, CSS + SASS.
 - Archestimator (archestimator.com) currently an ongoing project. a construction cost estimator for architects. Currently building with typescript, svelte, vite + rollup & supabase. Exploring moving to sveltekit once the framework becomes more stable.

Owner & Principal Architect

Architect Philip Jon E. Lewis - Private Practice

2016 - 2021

- · Owner & Principal Architect of Ar. Philip Jon E. Lewis, an architectural design practice.
 - The practice handled multiple architectural & interior projects but mainly consist of the commercial, office, & residential type. Handled 2-4 freelance staff at any one time.
 - Responsibilities mainly compose of client meetings and design proposal presentations and leading the design and management of the production of design and contract documents needed for building permits & actual construction.
 - Coordinated with multiple third party suppliers, engineers, mall administration and other allied fields with regards to the design, construction & completion of multiple projects.
 - · Scope of works include but are not limited to the following:
 - Client management
 - Contract negotiation
 - Architectural practice management
 - · Architectural design & development
 - Architectural Interiors
 - · Design proposal presentations
 - Supplier, Contractor & Engineering Coordination
 - CAD, Blueprints & Detailed Contract Documentation

Philip Jon Echavez Lewis UAP, PIA

Duly Registered & Licensed Architect, Republic of the Philippines Professional Regulatory Commission License Number: 00383344

Educational Background

Bachelor of Science in Architecture

The Pontifical & Royal University of Santo Tomas

2009 - 2015

- · Graduated with an Outstanding Thesis Award.
- Involved with various student organizations such as UAPSA-UST, Architect, Student Council & The Heritage Conservation Society.

High School Diploma

Elizabeth Seton School - Main Campus, Las Pinas City

2005 - 2009

Additional Work Experience

Assistant Architect & Planner

Architect Chona Elvas-Ponce, UAP

2015

- Created design, marketing & visualization materials in order to communicate the plan & vision of various projects and ssisted the principal architect in the planning & design of various masterplanned projects.
- Provided presentation drawings and renderings for a small scaled residential community that helped in client & project acquisition & completion.

Assistant Architect

Architect Charisse Ong, UAP

2014

- Assisted the principal architect in the 2D Encoding & 3D Modelling of various residential condominium fit out projects.
- Aided in the detection of clashes and errors in architectural & engineering drawings & documents.
- Built a strong relationship with the principal architect wherein she turned out to by one of my closest mentors and confidants up to the present.

Professional Certificates & Online Courses

Google

Through Coursera

- · Google Project Management
- Google UX Design

California Intitute of the Arts

Through Coursera

- UI / UX Design
- Graphic Design

UC Irvine

Through Coursera

· Project Management Principles & Practice

THe Hong Kong University of Science & Technology

Through Coursera

· Full Stack Web Development with React

Zero-To-Mastery Academy

Through Udemy

- · Complete Python Developer
- The Complete Web Developer
- JavaScript : The Advanced Concepts
- Complete Guide to Freelancing
- Complete Web & Mobile Designer: UI/UX & Figma.

Academind

Through Udemy

- MongoDB The Complete Developers Guide
- NodeJs The Complete Guide (MVC, REST API's, GraphQL, Deno)
- CSS The Complete Guide

Philip Jon Echavez Lewis UAP, PIA

Duly Registered & Licensed Architect, Republic of the Philippines Professional Regulatory Commission License Number : 00383344

Publications Appeared/Featured In

Shelter Magazine

Architecture Dichotomies

· Article: The Finer Class - A Continued Search for Architecture's Rising Vanguards

Awards & Recognitions

Outstanding Thesis Award

University Of Santo Tomas - College of Architecture

Seminars / Workshops Spoken At

Archive - Powered By Pecha Kucha

University of Santo Tomas - College of Architecture

UST Archinet - Architecture Network

Mulayin - Photoshop + Visualization & Post Processing Workshop

University of Santo Tomas - College of Architecture

UST College of Architecture Student Council

Ukit - Tracing Our Roots Through Philippine Architecture

University of Santo Tomas - College of Architecture

United Architects of the Philippines - Student Auxiliary UST Chapter

Ideate - Architecture Thesis Forum

University of Santo Tomas - College of Architecture

UST Scarlet Architecture & UST College of Architecture Student Council

Trivium - Business in Architecture

University of Santo Tomas - College of Architecture

UST Archinet - Architecture Network

Creative Career Planning for the 21st Century

Elizabeth Seton School - Main Campus Las Pinas City

Center for Student Well-Being of the Elizabeth Seton School

6th Architectural Thesis Forum - Breaking the Boundaries of Thesis Presentation

University of Santo Tomas - College of Architecture

UST Archinet - Architecture Network

Press Start - The College Survival Inspirational Talk

University of Santo Tomas - College of Architecture

UST Archinet - Architecture Network

Encore - The UST College of Architecture Outstanding Thesis Awardee Seminar

University of Santo Tomas - College of Architecture

UST Archinet - Architecture Network

Grafik - A Seminar on graphic design, visual layout & architectural presentation

University of Santo Tomas - College of Architecture

United Architects of the Philippines - Student Auxiliary UST Chapter

Et Cetera - Bare It All 9

University of Santo Tomas - College of Architecture

United Architects of the Philippines - Student Auxiliary UST Chapter

Philip Jon Echavez Lewis UAP, PIA

Duly Registered & Licensed Architect, Republic of the Philippines Professional Regulatory Commission License Number : 00383344

Professional Development & Associated Experiences

Advisory Board Member

United Architects of the Philippines - Student Auxiliary UST Chapter 2014 , 2016

Chapter President

United Architects of the Philippines - Graduate Auxiliary Manila Chapter 2015

Creative Director

University of Santo Tomas - College of Architecture Student Council 2013

Creative Director

19th UAPSA National Congress - United Architects of the Philippines - Student Auxiliary UST Chapter 2013

Philippine Delegate

4th Malaysian International Youth Programme 2012

Technical Director

UST Archinet - Architecture Network

2012

Chief-Of-Staff

United Architects of the Philippines - Student Auxiliary UST Chapter 2011

Philip Jon Echavez Lewis UAR, PIA

Duly Registered & Licensed Architect, Republic of the Philippines Professional Regulatory Commission License Number: 00383344

Other Professional Certificates & Courses

Mastering Typescript

· Colt Steele - Udemy

The Branding Masterclass - The Entire Brand Design Process

• Linday Marsh - Udemy

UX & Web Design Master Course

· Joe Natoli - Udemy

Master Digital Product Design: UX Research & UI Design

· Rob Sutcliffe - Udemy

Build a lucrative Copywriting Portfolio with Ease

· Tamsin Henderson - Udemy

The Complete Copywriting Course - Write to Sell Like a Pro

· Tamsin Henderson - Udemy

20 Web Projects with Vanilla Javascript

• Brad Traversy - Udemy

React Front to Back

· Brad Traversy - Udemy

Modern Javascript from the Beginning

· Brad Traversy - Udemy

Modern HTML & CSS From The Beginning (Including SASS)

• Brad Traversy - Udemy

NodeJS API Masterclass with Express & MongoDB

• Brad Traversy - Udemy

Probability and Statistics for Business and Data Science

• Jose Portilla - Udemy

Javascript Understanding the Weird Parts

• Anthony Alicea - Udemy

Statistics for Data Science & Business Analysis

• 365 Careers - Udemy

The Complete NodeJS Developer Course

• Andrew Mead, Rob Percival - Udemy

The Modern Javascript Bootcamp

• Andrew Mead - Udemy

Introduction to Corporate Finance

• Wharton Online : Through Coursera

Introduction to Financial Accounting

• Wharton Online: Through Coursera

Introduction to Marketing

• Wharton Online: Through Coursera

Managing Social and Human Capital

• Wharton Online : Through Coursera

Philip Jon Echavez Lewis UAP, PIA

Duly Registered & Licensed Architect, Republic of the Philippines Professional Regulatory Commission License Number : 00383344

Other Professional Certificates & Courses

The Strategy of Content Marketing

• University of California, Davis: Through Coursera

Business Writing

• University of Colorado, Boulder: Through Coursera

Graphic Design

· University of Colorado, Boulder: Through Coursera

Introduction to UI Design

• University of Minnesota: Through Coursera

Responsive Website Basics: Code with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript

• University of London: Through Coursera

Transacting on the BlockChain

• Insead : Through Coursera

Introduction to Blockchain Technologies

• Insead : Through Coursera

Digital Marketing

HubSpot Academy

Design Thinking & Global Startup

· Korean Advanced Institute of Sciente & Technology: Through Coursera

Digital Skills: User Experience

FutureLearn

Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner

• IBM